Irina Stamm

irina1@uchicago.edu +1 (847)-708-3614 Chicago, IL

https://www.linkedin.com/in/irina-stamm-bb9a68204/ https://github.com/bluairis

STATEMENT OF PURPOSE

My goal in the next stage of my career is to utilize my computational skills on new projects where I develop tools that enrich society. I am excited to learn and grow on the job and make myself a better technical specialist over time.

EDUCATION

The University of Chicago

Chicago, IL

Bachelor of Arts in Cognitive Science — GPA: 3.71/4.00

Expected Graduation, June 2024

Relevant Coursework: Introduction to Computer Science I/II, Introduction to Computer Programming, Introduction to Computer Systems, Discrete Mathematics, Theory of Algorithms, Statistical Methods and Applications, Undergraduate Computational Linguistics, Biotechnology in the 21st Century, Introduction to Digital Humanities, Data Visualization and Machine Learning, and Cognitive Modeling

WORK EXPERIENCE

University of Chicago Library

Chicago, IL

Digital Development Assistant

June 2021 -

Present

- Participated in a major UChicago library long term project for converting live exhibitions into virtual collections
- Developed a model framework for displaying current and future digital collections on the library website
- Personalized various front and back-end custom features for a website running on a Wagtail CMS
- Revamped the Mail Aliases Page by interacting with JSON data and developed brand new front end features

Data for the Common Good

Chicago, IL

Software Development Intern

June 2023 – August 2023

- Customized the Table-One Pediatric Intake Data Summary Tool to improve the logic of the data representation
- Analyzed the remaining flaws with the tool and recommended additional updates

Rosalind Franklin University

North Chicago, IL

Research Assistant

June 2019 – August 2019

- Studied the feasibility of an aqueous formulation of Aspirin with High Performance Liquid Chromatography
- Presented my research at the Women in Physical Sciences Conference at the University of Nebraska Lincoln

LEADERSHIP & ACTIVITIES

University of Chicago Uncommon Hacks

Chicago, IL

Technology Team Leader - Team Leader

September 2021 – Present

- Led a team in renovating and creating numerous website pages to ease hackathon registration
- Managed multiple separate sub-teams in achieving their respective goals in planning for Uncommon events

University of Chicago Model United Nationals

Chicago, IL

Assistant Chair - Deputy Director of Outreach

October 2022 – Present

- Advised international high school delegates on the content and delivery of their public speaking
- Gathered participant and sponsor contacts to increase registration and funding for MUNUC 2024 conference

SKILLS

Technical: Experienced with Databases, Object Oriented/Functional Programming, Github, SVN, Research, Data Analysis, Neural Networks, Machine Learning, and Adobe Suite

Professional: Strong Organizational and Analytical Skills, Goal Oriented, Team Player

Programming Languages: Proficient in Python, HTML, CSS, Java, Django, Javascript, SQL and JSON

Languages: English (Native), Russian (Native), Spanish (Fluent), French (Proficient)